<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: HCI | App Team 7]]></title>
  <link href="http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/categories/hci/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-26T18:54:39+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David, Kamil, Ke]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kamil's Heuristic Evaluation]]></title>
    <link href="http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2014/01/26/kamils-heuristic-evaluation/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-26T16:14:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2014/01/26/kamils-heuristic-evaluation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Defining tasks</h3>

<p>The tasks with which I assigned the team and myself to base our heuristic evaluations around are as shown below:</p>

<ul>
<li>Creating a patient stub with only the mandatory information</li>
<li>Creating a full patient record &ndash; navigating around most, if not all sections in a directed manner</li>
<li>Making amendments to data already entered into the app</li>
<li>Discarding a bad entry (before saving to server)</li>
</ul>


<p>These were based around tasks which were commonly discussed by our client during meetings. It should be noted however that due to time constraints, not all of our target features have are visibly completed &ndash; but the functionality exists in the raw code (needing to be &ldquo;wired up&rdquo;).</p>

<h3>Being critical</h3>

<h4>visibility of system status</h4>

<p>Android&rsquo;s action bar helped give a space for each page to be given a label, and so it&rsquo;s pretty easy to see where in the app the user is with a quick glance. However, one important sub-task that is currently lacking any visual indicator is saving. In the early stages of paper prototyping, I intended the save icon to change colour on first click, indicating that all items on the page have been saved &ndash; and disabling it from being touched again. Changing an item would then revert the icon to its original state. This would significantly reduce behaviour such as pressing the save button several times, in fear of losing data (which our client admits to doing).</p>

<h4>user control and freedom</h4>

<p>In designing the application, I ensured that most &ndash; if not all &ndash; key pages are accessible within 3 taps. This was made possible by allowing the navigation drawer to be accessed from all data entry pages within the app. However, as I have noticed in preliminary user feedback from colleagues and our client, accessing the Patient Details page to correct a value was not entirely intuitive, and could be improved.</p>

<h4>error prevention</h4>

<p>Unfortunately, the system does not prevent you from &ldquo;submitting&rdquo; an incomplete record at present (MINAP requires the completion of 4 mandatory fields before submission). This was primarily due to lack of time to integrate this business logic, but is admittedly a key feature for MINAP.</p>

<p>Data destroying activities such as discarding bad entries are however accompanied by easy to understand warnings before being carried out.</p>

<h4>aesthetic and minimalist design</h4>

<p>The app looks absolutely brilliant for its purpose as a proof of concept app. The grey look was kept to allow for future styling by MINAP after the application has been fully handed over. I&rsquo;ve also found that people can spend hours trying to decide how things should be coloured and how images should look &ndash; something I decided to avoid in creating the app design.</p>

<p>Of course, I&rsquo;m biased&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ke's Heuristic Evaluation]]></title>
    <link href="http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2014/01/25/kes-heuristic-evaluation/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-25T10:09:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2014/01/25/kes-heuristic-evaluation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following evaluation is based on Nielsen’s 10 principles of heuristic evaluation:</p>

<h3>Visibility of system status (Feedback)</h3>

<p>The system should always keep users informed about what is going on, through appropriate feedback within reasonable time.</p>

<h4>Selection</h4>

<p>The box that was clicked by user will be highlighted with blue line, makes it easier for user to know where they have selected</p>

<p><img src="/images/ke-selection.jpg" title="Selection" ></p>

<h4>Save indicator</h4>

<p>A feedback message is displayed when an action is performed, in case, when save button is clicked, the app will save completed fields and give feedback to user.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ke-save.jpg" title="Save" ></p>

<h3>Match between system and the real world(METHAPHOR)</h3>

<p>The system should speak the users' language, with words, phrases and concepts familiar to the user, rather than system-oriented terms. Follow real-world conventions, making information appear in a natural and logical order.</p>

<p>The design of navigation page on the app is very similar to the one that the current MINAP web solution has, expect the simplified structure, the essential feature which is the tree diagram was kept, and the logical relations between pages are inherited as well. For those who are new to our app, they can easily find their way by using the familiar navigation page.</p>

<p>Navigation page on the app</p>

<p><img src="/images/ke-system-1.jpg" title="Current app" ></p>

<p>Navigation page on the old web solution</p>

<p><img src="/images/ke-system-2.jpg" title="Web app" ></p>

<h3>User control and freedom (NAVIGATION)</h3>

<p>Users often choose system functions by mistake and will need a clearly marked &ldquo;emergency exit&rdquo; to leave the unwanted state without having to go through an extended dialogue. Support undo and redo.</p>

<p>The app provides excellent navigation supports. Both an easy navigation side bar and a navigation page are offered to user. For those who are new to our app, they can easily find their way by using the familiar navigation page, for those who want quickly switch from page to page, the navigation bar will meet their need.</p>

<p>The navigation page</p>

<p><img src="/images/ke-control-1.jpg" title="Navigation map" ></p>

<p>The navigation bar</p>

<p><img src="/images/ke-control-2.jpg" title="Navigation drawer" ></p>

<h3>Consistency and standards</h3>

<p>Users should not have to wonder whether different words, situations, or actions mean the same thing. Follow platform conventions.</p>

<h4>Input method</h4>

<p>In order to make the user as comfortable as possible, the app inherited the way user input the information from the old web solution, the ratio button, drop down list, the types of the fields were all kept as they were.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ke-consistency.jpg" title="Input methods" ></p>

<h3>Error prevention</h3>

<p>Even better than good error messages is a careful design which prevents a problem from occurring in the first place. Either eliminate error-prone conditions or check for them and present users with a confirmation option before they commit to the action.</p>

<p>The log out and create new record functions both will discard the current record, in order to prevent user mistakenly touched those buttons and lose their input, a warming sign will pop up to confirm whether user wants to proceed.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ke-error.jpg" title="Error handling" ></p>

<h3>Recognition rather than recall</h3>

<p>Minimize the user&rsquo;s memory load by making objects, actions, and options visible. The user should not have to remember information from one part of the dialogue to another. Instructions for use of the system should be visible or easily retrievable whenever appropriate.</p>

<p>In case the user need help with understanding certain fields, most of the fields are come with notes, if you click the exclamation mark next to the field name, the note which contains explanation for the field will appear.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ke-recog.jpg" title="Recognition" ></p>

<h3>Flexibility and efficiency of use</h3>

<p>Accelerators &mdash; unseen by the novice user &mdash; may often speed up the interaction for the expert user such that the system can cater to both inexperienced and experienced users. Allow users to tailor frequent actions.</p>

<p>The reason why the app has two navigation methods is not only the new user could get use to the app very quickly(with navigation page), but also those experienced user, who wants be more efferent, could switch from page to page more quickly(with navigation bar).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[David's Heuristic Evaluation]]></title>
    <link href="http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2014/01/21/davids-heuristic-evaluation/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-21T02:17:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2014/01/21/davids-heuristic-evaluation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Throughout this project, I&rsquo;ve been mostly involved with the back-end logic and design, and though my &ldquo;share&rdquo; has its importance, in the end it is the user interface that will be presented to our end users. Having said that, using the mobile application was, for this particular user, a painless experience.</p>

<p>There is familiarity in the way the application is presented. As of this writing, our application is not complete; yet I can&rsquo;t help but make parallels between the existing web application and our solution. The way input is asked from the user is identical on both applications: radio buttons, drop-down lists, text / date fields are all included, work and (for the most part, given the reduced working space) are presented in the same order. Functionally, our solution works as the web application does. A record needs only four fields be filled in order to be saved, but provides enough fields to complete six full information pages.</p>

<p>The overall design of our solution is, for lack of a better term, aesthetically sound. There are no elements that go unused or misused, everything on the screen is there for a clear reason. Furthermore, the design is clean. Colours are used sparingly, but contrast well when needed (especially on radio button selection).</p>

<p>Navigation has remained faithful to the web application as well. Next and Back buttons work on our app as they do online, keeping a linear approach. Yet the addition of a drawer navigation object will allow for faster navigation and data input for those users that may be more experienced than most. Slight reminders or visual cues, the clearest one being having to scroll down to the end of the page in order to continue, make for a more user friendly experience.</p>

<p>As a final note, it should be pointed out that this application is meant for medical professionals. As such, terminology is not suited for all users. Tooltips also will only help those that are familiar with MINAP and their web application.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A quick update...]]></title>
    <link href="http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2014/01/20/a-quick-update-dot-dot-dot/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-20T15:30:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2014/01/20/a-quick-update-dot-dot-dot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I haven&rsquo;t quite had the time to update this blog over the holiday season and since our last client meeting due to large amounts of Android coding. I can however safely say that all the outlined interactions have been implemented in its final form, pending hooking up to David&rsquo;s back-end. The app should currently serve its main purpose as a tool to gather feedback on the concept of data collection for MINAP on a mobile phone.</p>

<p>A run-through of how our app functions will be outlined in a future video, but here&rsquo;s a collage of screenshots to update you on the progress of the overall interactions the user can have with the app (note: for clarity, many pages have been left out):</p>

<p><img src="/images/app-screenshots.png" title="MINAP mobile app screenshots" ></p>

<p>And just to show how closely the Android app resembles the initial paper prototypes:</p>

<p><img src="/images/progress.JPG" title="Progress!" ></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trying to be responsive]]></title>
    <link href="http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2014/01/13/trying-to-be-responsive/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-13T17:33:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2014/01/13/trying-to-be-responsive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Client feedback</h3>

<p>Today we had our first meeting (since breaking for the holiday) with our client with a working prototype of our Android app. Again, comments on the app were generally positive, with some minor nitpicks on functionality (the realm of product specifications). I did however bring up the idea of porting the app to a tablet interface, seeing how our survey indicated the current use of tablets (iPads) in some hospitals.</p>

<p>Once again, the navigation drawer was the topic of conversation &ndash; however, this time it was much more positive. Our client was willing to scrap the navigation map in favour of a persistent navigation drawer, as it served the purpose of navigation much better. One thing to note however, is that the navigation map also serves as an indicator of page completion in the web app, changing the colours of each box, depending on completion status.</p>

<p>This did however get me thinking about a possible tablet interface that gave the best of both worlds.</p>

<h3>How responsive is enough?</h3>

<p>The current Android app (screenshots will be available in future posts&hellip;) scales the input boxes and value labels to the screen width, and the navigation map should also scale to the phone size. This works well for phones, where the extra real estate is welcome &ndash; however, this looks terrible on a larger tablet screen, creating extremely long lines of text and wasted space for data entry pages.</p>

<p>The extra space would ideally be used to contain data entry fields in separate &lsquo;columns&rsquo;, more akin to the current web app. However, to properly implement this would require another iteration of design &ndash; which we can&rsquo;t afford the time to do. However, some quick prototypes of possible tablet layout designs are suggested below:</p>

<p>The primary view would consist of a persistent navigation drawer, with the navigation map taking up most of the screen real estate &ndash; similar to the current web view.</p>

<p><img src="/images/tablet-1.png" title="Tablet main view" ></p>

<p>The &lsquo;fragment&rsquo; containing the navigation map would be replaced when navigating into a data entry page, showing a view (also) very similar to the web app.</p>

<p><img src="/images/tablet-2.png" title="Tablet data entry view" ></p>

<p>The design process for our app to best fit a tablet view evidently boils down to just mimicking the current web app interface. Future work on this should be fairly straightforward (layouts can be separated to allow for this).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
