<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: HCI | App Team 7]]></title>
  <link href="http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/categories/hci/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-25T20:12:49+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David, Kamil, Ke]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ke's Heuristic Evaluation]]></title>
    <link href="http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2014/01/25/kes-heuristic-evaluation/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-25T10:09:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2014/01/25/kes-heuristic-evaluation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The following evaluation is based on Nielsen’s 10 principles of heuristic evaluation:</p>

<h3>Visibility of system status (Feedback)</h3>

<p>The system should always keep users informed about what is going on, through appropriate feedback within reasonable time.</p>

<h4>Selection</h4>

<p>The box that was clicked by user will be highlighted with blue line, makes it easier for user to know where they have selected</p>

<p><img src="/images/ke-selection.jpg" title="Selection" ></p>

<h4>Save indicator</h4>

<p>A feedback message is displayed when an action is performed, in case, when save button is clicked, the app will save completed fields and give feedback to user.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ke-save.jpg" title="Save" ></p>

<h3>Match between system and the real world(METHAPHOR)</h3>

<p>The system should speak the users' language, with words, phrases and concepts familiar to the user, rather than system-oriented terms. Follow real-world conventions, making information appear in a natural and logical order.</p>

<p>The design of navigation page on the app is very similar to the one that the current MINAP web solution has, expect the simplified structure, the essential feature which is the tree diagram was kept, and the logical relations between pages are inherited as well. For those who are new to our app, they can easily find their way by using the familiar navigation page.</p>

<p>Navigation page on the app</p>

<p><img src="/images/ke-system-1.jpg" title="Current app" ></p>

<p>Navigation page on the old web solution</p>

<p><img src="/images/ke-system-2.jpg" title="Web app" ></p>

<h3>User control and freedom (NAVIGATION)</h3>

<p>Users often choose system functions by mistake and will need a clearly marked &ldquo;emergency exit&rdquo; to leave the unwanted state without having to go through an extended dialogue. Support undo and redo.</p>

<p>The app provides excellent navigation supports. Both an easy navigation side bar and a navigation page are offered to user. For those who are new to our app, they can easily find their way by using the familiar navigation page, for those who want quickly switch from page to page, the navigation bar will meet their need.</p>

<p>The navigation page</p>

<p><img src="/images/ke-control-1.jpg" title="Navigation map" ></p>

<p>The navigation bar</p>

<p><img src="/images/ke-control-2.jpg" title="Navigation drawer" ></p>

<h3>Consistency and standards</h3>

<p>Users should not have to wonder whether different words, situations, or actions mean the same thing. Follow platform conventions.</p>

<h4>Input method</h4>

<p>In order to make the user as comfortable as possible, the app inherited the way user input the information from the old web solution, the ratio button, drop down list, the types of the fields were all kept as they were.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ke-consistency.jpg" title="Input methods" ></p>

<h3>Error prevention</h3>

<p>Even better than good error messages is a careful design which prevents a problem from occurring in the first place. Either eliminate error-prone conditions or check for them and present users with a confirmation option before they commit to the action.</p>

<p>The log out and create new record functions both will discard the current record, in order to prevent user mistakenly touched those buttons and lose their input, a warming sign will pop up to confirm whether user wants to proceed.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ke-error.jpg" title="Error handling" ></p>

<h3>Recognition rather than recall</h3>

<p>Minimize the user&rsquo;s memory load by making objects, actions, and options visible. The user should not have to remember information from one part of the dialogue to another. Instructions for use of the system should be visible or easily retrievable whenever appropriate.</p>

<p>In case the user need help with understanding certain fields, most of the fields are come with notes, if you click the exclamation mark next to the field name, the note which contains explanation for the field will appear.</p>

<p><img src="/images/ke-recog.jpg" title="Recognition" ></p>

<h3>Flexibility and efficiency of use</h3>

<p>Accelerators &mdash; unseen by the novice user &mdash; may often speed up the interaction for the expert user such that the system can cater to both inexperienced and experienced users. Allow users to tailor frequent actions.</p>

<p>The reason why the app has two navigation methods is not only the new user could get use to the app very quickly(with navigation page), but also those experienced user, who wants be more efferent, could switch from page to page more quickly(with navigation bar).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[David's Heuristic Evaluation]]></title>
    <link href="http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2014/01/21/davids-heuristic-evaluation/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-21T02:17:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2014/01/21/davids-heuristic-evaluation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Throughout this project, I&rsquo;ve been mostly involved with the back-end logic and design, and though my &ldquo;share&rdquo; has its importance, in the end it is the user interface that will be presented to our end users. Having said that, using the mobile application was, for this particular user, a painless experience.</p>

<p>There is familiarity in the way the application is presented. As of this writing, our application is not complete; yet I can&rsquo;t help but make parallels between the existing web application and our solution. The way input is asked from the user is identical on both applications: radio buttons, drop-down lists, text / date fields are all included, work and (for the most part, given the reduced working space) are presented in the same order. Functionally, our solution works as the web application does. A record needs only four fields be filled in order to be saved, but provides enough fields to complete six full information pages.</p>

<p>The overall design of our solution is, for lack of a better term, aesthetically sound. There are no elements that go unused or misused, everything on the screen is there for a clear reason. Furthermore, the design is clean. Colours are used sparingly, but contrast well when needed (especially on radio button selection).</p>

<p>Navigation has remained faithful to the web application as well. Next and Back buttons work on our app as they do online, keeping a linear approach. Yet the addition of a drawer navigation object will allow for faster navigation and data input for those users that may be more experienced than most. Slight reminders or visual cues, the clearest one being having to scroll down to the end of the page in order to continue, make for a more user friendly experience.</p>

<p>As a final note, it should be pointed out that this application is meant for medical professionals. As such, terminology is not suited for all users. Tooltips also will only help those that are familiar with MINAP and their web application.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Playing With Paper]]></title>
    <link href="http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2013/12/20/playing-with-paper/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-20T14:02:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2013/12/20/playing-with-paper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Placeholder text for Kamil&rsquo;s blog post detailing the process of UI paper prototyping and client feedback.</em></p>

<p><div class="embed-video-container"><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/yi91OxmUkG8 "></iframe></div></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Android UI Elements]]></title>
    <link href="http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2013/12/19/android-ui-elements/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-19T14:02:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2013/12/19/android-ui-elements</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve owned an Android smartphone for three years before switching over to a hand-me-down iPhone, and went through Gingerbread and Ice Cream Sandwich(4.0). Having spent the first 2 years dealing with Gingerbread, switching to the new interface of Android 4.0 was a breath of fresh air. ICS introduced a cleaner UI with a clearer design language. Our decision to only support devices from ICS onwards are primarily due to security concerns, but the availability of more (intuitive) UI elements and ways to present our app is really just the icing on the cake.</p>

<p>To get a clearer idea of the UI elements available to us, I had a look through the official Android UI website, identifying the main elements available for use. This was just a very brief run through, as I realised the documentation regarding the recommended use of the elements by Google were quite thorough &ndash; which I intend to constantly refer to throughout the building of the app UI.</p>

<p>Platform specific UI patterns of interest (images taken from the <a href="http://developer.android.com/design/patterns/index.html">Android developer website</a>:</p>

<h4>Action Bar</h4>

<p><img src="/images/action_bar_basics.png" title="Action Bar image from the Android Developer website" >
The action bar acts as a persistent UI pattern that can be used across all pages. Less important functionality such as Logging out could be kept in the &lsquo;overflow&rsquo; (3 vertical dots) menu, and key features such as saving could use prominent icons (the classical floppy disk). The icon (labelled 1) for ancestral navigation could also be made contextual, such that it could change to be a compass icon when the user navigates to a data entry page.</p>

<h4>Navigation drawer</h4>

<p><img src="/images/navigation_drawer_overview.png" title="Navigation Drawer image from the Android Developer website" >
Our mobile app&rsquo;s key purpose is to allow for quick data collection at the point of contact with the patient. As such, we would like to include as many shortcuts to frequently accessed features as possible. The navigation drawer could be introduced as an alternative way to navigate around the pages, as opposed to constantly visiting the navigation map. The typical way of navigation (according to our client) involves the user &lsquo;hopping&rsquo; around different pages when entering information (making the back and next buttons redundant &ndash; but we are keeping them for familiarity). A good use of the drawer would be to allow quick navigation around pages, as well as maybe giving the user feedback on who they are logged in as, and who the current patient being recorded is.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Android Design]]></title>
    <link href="http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2013/12/19/android-design/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-19T14:02:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2013/12/19/android-design</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>To create a truly native application that users of the mobile platform can easily navigate, I figured that I needed to understand the common design language of the operating system (OS). So in preparation for mapping information and navigation of the current MINAP web app onto Android, I had a look through the <a href="http://developer.android.com/design/get-started/principles.html">official design principles of Android OS</a>. At first glance, the Android design principles don&rsquo;t seem to relate to our medical data entry app at all (&ldquo;delight me in surprising ways&rdquo;?), but specific points can be picked out. From the three main principles (Enchant me, Simplify my life, Make me amazing), some outlined sub-principles of the document can be taken onboard in the design of the app:</p>

<h3>Simplify My Life</h3>

<h4>Keep it brief:</h4>

<p>Although the core content of the app cannot be changed due to the precise nature of medical data input, we can keep our tutorials short with simple language</p>

<h4>Only show what I need when I need it:</h4>

<p>Breaking down the tasks of using the application strikes me as an area which we could improve on the current app, with a wealth of possible options available to me upon opening the web app. If we expect the app to have more widespread usage, the process of record creation should be fairly intuitive to someone with limited prior knowledge.</p>

<h4>I should always know where I am:</h4>

<p>There are two main &lsquo;modes&rsquo; which our user would be most active in during use: navigation mode, and page data entry mode. It should be clear how the user will navigate back and forth through the app, allowing for multiple possible ways (i.e. back button, or a navigator icon)</p>

<h4>Never lose my stuff:</h4>

<p>Due to security concerns and data protection, we shouldn&rsquo;t retain a local copy of entered data beyond the duration of the session. Despite this, we could &lsquo;autosave&rsquo; the entered data into a &lsquo;draft&rsquo; database on the central server, with visual indicators to let the user know the data has been submitted for storing (the expected web app behaviour is manual saving).</p>

<h4>If it looks the same, it should act the same:</h4>

<p>We should keep in mind what we mean when using Android UI elements (i.e. if it looks like a text box, it should act like one) to ensure they retain the same meaning throughout the app.</p>

<h3>Make Me Amazing</h3>

<h4>Give me tricks that work everywhere:</h4>

<p>Gestures such as swiping from the edge for menus aren&rsquo;t good for a primary interface due to discoverability issues for novice users, but can serve to speed up the workflow of more experienced users.</p>

<h4>It&rsquo;s not my fault:</h4>

<p>When informing the user of validation errors, it would be helpful to consider if the warnings could be reworded for clarity and &lsquo;niceness&rsquo;.</p>

<h4>Make important things fast:</h4>

<p>The ability to switch between pages and the mode of data entry and navigation should be effortless. It should also be relatively easy to check details of the session such as the current logged in username and patient core details.</p>

<p>To make UI decisions easier, I will be aiming to follow these principles as closely as possible in conjunction with the core Android UI elements and more detailed design guidelines which I hope to cover in a future post.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
