<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: David | App Team 7]]></title>
  <link href="http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/categories/david/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-19T14:25:22+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David, Kamil, Ke]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Looking Inside]]></title>
    <link href="http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2013/12/15/looking-inside/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-15T14:01:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2013/12/15/looking-inside</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Placeholder text for David&rsquo;s blog post for current web app analysis.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coming Out]]></title>
    <link href="http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2013/12/14/coming-out/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-14T12:09:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2013/12/14/coming-out</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>Placeholder text for David&rsquo;s blog post for client &amp; project background.</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet Julie]]></title>
    <link href="http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2013/12/02/meet-julie/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-02T17:39:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2013/12/02/meet-julie</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In order to get a better grasp on the usability and usage of the project. The team would like to introduce our persona, Julie.</p>

<p><img class="<a" src="href="http://placekitten.com/200/200">http://placekitten.com/200/200</a>" title="Place Kitten" ></p>

<p>Julie is a 28-year-old Nurse working in the General Hospital (MINAP Code: YYY). She is in charge of admitting and taking care of all types of patients at General Hospital.</p>

<p>Due to budget constraints, Julie cares for multiple patients at the same time gathering data for other organizations in addition to MINAP. Since entering a patient&rsquo;s data for MINAP&rsquo;s web application requires being physically in front of a computer as well as time to complete the record, Julie finds the whole process &ldquo;unwieldy&rdquo;.</p>

<p>Julie is tech-savvy in that she owns a smartphone, she has never used it for work, though. However, as she has some time with the patient while they are being admitted, Julie wonders if she could at least flag the patient for later input to MINAP&rsquo;s database through her smartphone.</p>

<p>As she checks in a new patient, Julie wonders&hellip; &ldquo;Is there an app for that?&rdquo;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Week 4]]></title>
    <link href="http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2013/12/02/week-4/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-02T14:44:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2013/12/02/week-4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Monday &ndash; Nov. 25th</h3>

<hr />

<p>The App Dev team decided it would be in everyone&rsquo;s best interest if no coding took place the day after the University&rsquo;s deadline. Instead, the team looked ahead to the second deadline three weeks away. Wiki resources were updated, Milestone 2 requirements were read and understood. Finally, we presented our client with a possible survey to be used for data gathering / analytics.</p>

<h3>Tuesday &ndash; Nov. 26th</h3>

<hr />

<p>Per our client&rsquo;s wishes, the dataset has been reduced to 60 fields from 130 fields. The team first fleshed out how these reduced dataset would interact within the application. Abstraction was taken into account as all most of these fields would require alike functionality.</p>

<p>After separating the fields into logical &ldquo;pages,&rdquo; the meeting focused on the transition from Java coding to integrating SQL and XML into the product&rsquo;s code.</p>

<h3>Wednesday &ndash; Nov. 27th</h3>

<hr />

<p>The team reviewed extra documents from client that further helped with dataset rules. Sample decisions trees were sketched as per the new validation logic. Meeting was adjourned after an email to client with some questions for clarifications was sent.</p>

<h3>Thursday &ndash; Nov. 28th</h3>

<hr />

<p>The client&rsquo;s reply cleared all questions from previous meeting. After discussing this new information, the team focused on University tasks, namely the GC02 poster that would be due next Wednesday (the 4th).</p>

<p>After a brief discussion. It was decided that meetings for Friday and the weekend (the 29th through Dec 1st) would be unnecessary. As such, the team divvied up work packages to clear during these days including:</p>

<ul>
<li>Making sure Java validation works on a command line level</li>
<li>Making sure XML parsing works on a command line level</li>
<li>Making sure SQL connection / read / write capabilities work on a command line level</li>
<li>Further insight into Android programming, HCI requirements</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Week 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2013/11/25/week-3/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-25T14:41:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://akz08.github.io/minap-mobile/blog/2013/11/25/week-3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Monday &ndash; Nov. 18th</h3>

<hr />

<p>As the first milestone draws close, the team started the meeting with a review of the project&rsquo;s specifications both from the client and from the University. We then moved to advance the parts that were lacking. Use cases were tabulated. Further git run-throughs were underway. Finally, our latest meeting with our client was transcribed and questions and answers were extracted from it.</p>

<h3>Tuesday &ndash; Nov. 19th</h3>

<hr />

<p>The entire team concentrated on coding.</p>

<p>It was deemed one more client meeting was needed before sending in the project for marking. The team wrote down all questions that may have been left out of previous communications as well as drafting out a survey prototype per client&rsquo;s suggestion.</p>

<p>Meeting was adjourned after considering a Gantt chart for drafting out the schedule of the work packages.</p>

<h3>Wednesday &ndash; Nov. 20th</h3>

<hr />

<p>Our meeting with our client and the web application&rsquo;s developer went as expected. We followed up with the developer on some clarification due to the complexities of both our project and the existing web app.</p>

<p>Once again, the team checked the project&rsquo;s specifications and listed the yet unfinished sections.</p>

<h3>Thursday &ndash; Nov. 21st through Sunday Nov. 24th</h3>

<hr />

<p>The team worked throughout the rest of the week on any and all missing sections of the project.</p>

<p>Coding took place throughout most of these four days. During coding breaks, the team worked on the project report, Gantt chart, data dictionary, or UML specifications.</p>

<p>On Sunday, November 24th, at 4:52 P.M., the team gathered all it sources and turned the project in for marking.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
